stylebop.com 2017-02-04

# Privacy & Data Protection | Luxury fashion online | STYLEBOP.com

### Privacy and Data Protection

Thank you for visiting stylebop.com! We would like to explain which private data we use when you visit STYLEBOP.com, why we do this and how we do this.

* * *

### 1\. Contact details

Stylebop GmbH, Maria-Merian-Straße 7, 85521 Ottobrunn/München, Germany (“STYLEBOP”, “STYLEBOP.com”, “we“) is responsible for your privacy protection and is the official service provider. You can find further information about our company and complete contact information under [Imprint](https://www.stylebop.com/en-de/women/imprint).

Should you have further questions regarding privacy protection, please contact us at [privacy@stylebop.com](mailto:privacy@stylebop.com) or via any contact stated in our [Imprint](https://www.stylebop.com/en-de/women/imprint).

* * *

### 2\. Use of our website

Every time you use our website your browser transfers certain technical details to the server, where the information you need is stored (for example the name of the needed file, date and time of use, browser type, showed websites and error messages). For technical and statistical reasons such data is stored in the so called log files on the server. No personal information or IP addresses are stored in such log files and with the help of these log files it is not possible to identify what information you accessed on our website.

Moreover, any personal information (for example your name or contact information) will be transferred to us only when you explicitly provide this information to us for certain purposes, for example when you register on our website or place an order. We use your personal data either for certain purposes (for example for processing your order) or in case you explicitly allow us to do this or in case we must or have the right to do this according to existing laws.

2.1. Creating a STYLEBOP-account / My Account

When you register a new STYLEBOP-account (My account), you must provide the following information:

  * Title
  * Your first and last name
  * Your email adress
  * A password for your new account

Providing other information is optional. We will use the data provided for creating your STYLEBOP account. We use any optional information according to our privacy policy and in order to personalize our services, including your STYLEBOP account.

2.2. Order processing

We store and use order details to carry out the delivery to the address provided and for further order processing purposes. When necessary (for example during payment or delivery) your personal information is passed over to third parties, like a payment provider or shipping partner.

2.3. Use of your email address for advertising purposes

If you have already purchased any products on stylebop.com we use your data to the extent allowed by law to send you emails advertising similar products or offers.

You can reject such use of your data any time at no cost. In each email you will find a deactivation link. Alternatively you can contact us regarding this via any contact provided in our [Imprint](https://www.stylebop.com/en-de/women/imprint).

* * *

### 3\. Newsletter / Fashion News

On our website you can provide us with your email address and further optional information, so that in the future we can send you regular emails with Fashion News, information regarding special offers running on stylebop.com and other news.

We will use your email address only for sending Fashion News to you. Optional information is not necessary for signing up for Fashion News. This optional information will be used only for personalizing your Fashion News and other online offers to the extent allowed by this privacy policy.

For signing up for Fashion News we use the so called Double-Opt-in procedure. It means that after providing your email address you will receive a confirmation email, where we ask you to confirm your email address.

Fashion News include such usual market technologies as pixel tracking or random IDs, which help us to assess the use of Fashion News by our customers. They help us to understand which information interests you more and which products and news is more interesting to you. All data is always stored under pseudonym and is not merged with other data (for example customer number, name, address, order details).

**Unsubscribe.** : You can unsubscribe from Fashion News at any time using the unsubscribe link provided in each email. Alternatively you can unsubscribe from Fashion News by using any contact provided in our [Imprint](https://www.stylebop.com/en-de/women/imprint) If you unsubscribe we will delete your email address and any optional information in case provided. Please note that any data provided during the account registration or ordering process will not be deleted if you unsubscribe the Fashion News. 

* * *

### 4\. Cookies

Our website uses cookies. A "cookie" is a small standard text file that is stored by your browser when you use our website for the first time. When you use our website again your browser sends the information to the server with the text information, which was stored in the cookie before. A typical cookie contains information about your system or a random string as an identification number, which allows stylebop.com to recognize your browser and to link it to your previous visit of our website.

We use cookies to make the use of stylebop.com more comfortable and customer friendly. For example cookies allow you to put items into the shopping bag and make changes to your existing shopping bag. Cookies also help to save your website options (for example language, country and payment method) for the future visits.

Furthermore we use cookies to the extent allowed by this privacy policy to collect statistical data regarding the general consumer behaviour. Thanks to the evaluation of this data we can get a better picture of our customers’ needs so that we can improve our website and users’ experience. 

* * *

### 5\. Analytics

5.1. Google Analytics

The STYLEBOP.com website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service from Google Inc. Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies” to create pseudonymised user profiles. The information that the cookie generates about your use of this website is transferred to and stored on a server operated by Google in the USA. Google uses this information on the name of STYLEBOP.com to evaluate your usage of our website, to compile reports on web activities for the site host and to perform other services associated with website and internet use for market research purposes. 

In no case will Google associate your IP address with other Google data. As we have activated IP anonymization for our website, the IP addresses that are automatically transmitted with the usage details are abbreviated by Google within the European Union or other contracting states of the European Economic Area before the data is forwarded to and stored in the USA.

You may also prevent the recording of the data generated by the cookie and concerning your usage of the website (including your IP address) by Google and to the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing the browser [plugin](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de). If you use our website on a mobile device, please use [this link](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/user-opt-out) to prevent the use of Google Analytics. After this an opt-out-cookie will be used, which prevents the transfer of any data to Google. Please note that you should use this link again in case you deleted the cookie from your mobile device or in case you wish to prevent the work of Google Analytics on another mobile device. The opt-out-cookie does not prevent the use of Goggle Analytics on other websites.

You can find further information on Google Analytics in privacy policy of Google under<http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html>.

5.2. econda

In order to improve stylebop.com we also use the web analysis provided by econda GmbH (econda). Econda collects the user data during the use of our website and creates pseudonymised user profiles. Cookies could be used for these purposes. In no case will the collected data be associated with other user’s data. IP-addresses will be anonymized immediately after the collection, which prevents that the user’s profile can be associated with a certain IP-address.

You may also prevent the recording and storing of the data in the future by clicking [here](http://www.econda.de/econda/unternehmen/datenschutz/widerspruchscookie/). After this an opt-out-cookie will be used, which prevents the transfer of any data. Please note that this link works only for the devise and browser used when clicking on the link. If you delete the opt-out-cookie or use on another browser, you will need to click on the link provided above again.

* * *

### 6\. Retargeting

Stylebop.com uses so-called retargeting technologies. Retargeting allows us to address internet users, who previously visited stylebop.com, by personalised advertising on other websites. Just like analytics, retargeting uses only pseudonymised data records. This technology uses cookies with random IDs. These IDs as well as your browsing history cannot be allocated to you. Below you will receive the information regarding retargeting services we use. You will also find out how you can prevent the corresponding data use with the help of opt-out cookies. Please note that an opt-out cookie should be used for each browser separately. If you delete all cookies from your browser, then the opt-out cookie will also be deleted.

6.1. Sociomantic

We use retargeting services provided by sociomantic labs GmbH, Paul-Lincke-Ufer 39/40, 10999 Berlin (“Sociomantic”). You can prevent the use of data by Sociomantic by clicking on [https://www.sociomantic.com/privacy/en](https://www.sociomantic.com/privacy/en/) and checking the provided “opt-out” box. An opt-out cookie will be installed in your browser that will let Sociomantic know that no data can be used and processed. 

6.2. Criteo

We use retargeting services provided by Criteo S.A., Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France (“Criteo”). You can prevent the use of data by Criteo by clicking on <http://www.criteo.com/privacy/> and checking the provided “opt-out” box. An opt-out cookie will be installed in your browser that will let Criteo know that no data can be used and processed.

6.3. Facebook

We use retargeting service “Custom Audiences” provided by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (“Facebook”). For this purpose we introduce the so called “Facebook pixel”. When you browse on our website, your browser automatically connects to Facebook servers and installs a cookie in your browser. Facebook receives the information that your IP address was browsing our website. Facebook uses this information for providing us anonymous statistics regarding the use of our website and the efficiency of our Facebook ads. If you have an account on Facebook and allowed Facebook to do this in your privacy settings, Facebook will allocate the received information to your Facebook profile in order to use it for targeted Facebook ads. You can find further information on Facebook privacy policy under <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>. You can check and change your Facebook privacy settings by clicking [here](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads). If you do not have a Facebook account, you can prevent Facebook from data processing by clicking on deactivation link on YourOnlineChoices website, provided by European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance: <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices>. If you deactivate Facebook data processing, Facebook will only show you ads created according to information other than collected with the help of retargeting tags.

* * *

### 7\. Social-Plug-ins

Auf stylebop.com kommen sogenannte „Social-Plug-ins“ zum Einsatz. Dabei handelt es sich um kleine Schaltflächen von sozialen Netzwerken, die Sie betätigen können, um mit Anderen beispielsweise den Inhalt einer Webseite auf stylebop.com zu teilen. Die Schaltflächen werden von dem jeweiligen sozialen Netzwerk bereitgestellt.

7.1. Facebook

Facebook is a social network owned by Facebook Ireland Limited, Hanover Reach, 5-7 Hanover Quay, Dublin 2 Ireland (“Facebook”). Facebook-Plug-ins are marked with blue Facebook logo and have as a rule the corresponding function (for example “Like” or “Share”).

If you use a Facebook plug-in on stylebop.com, your browser automatically connects to Facebook servers and starts the plug-in. In this case Facebook will automatically receive the information that the plug-in was activated on stylebop.com. If you click on the corresponding icon, it is possible that further information about you will be processed by Facebook. It is possible that Facebook will use a cookie, which helps Facebook to remember that you clicked the corresponding icon on stylebop.com. If you are logged in on Facebook while browsing our website Facebook can allocate your activity to your Facebook profile. If you log in on Facebook after clicking on the corresponding icon on our website, it is possible that this information will be posted in your Facebook profile or your feed. In this case Facebook may use and store further information. It is possible that in this case Facebook creates user profiles, which contain more information than your Facebook profile.

We are not able to influence which information is used and stored by Facebook and for which purposes and therefore are not liable for Facebook data processing. You will find further information on data processing and your corresponding rights in the Facebook privacy policy. You can see the Facebook privacy policy under <https://www.facebook.com/policy.php>.

We never know which Facebook plug-ins you use. We only receive anonymous statistics from Facebook regarding Facebook plug-ins used on stylebop.com within a certain period of time.

7.2. Google+

Google+ is a social network owned by Google. Google+ plug-ins are marked with “g+1”.

When you browse our website and use Google+ plug-in your browser will automatically connect with Google servers and load the plug-in. In this case Google will automatically receive the information that the plug-in was activated on stylebop.com. Google+ plug-ins will be automatically transferred from Google to your browser. Therefore we cannot influence the data volume used by Google. According to information from Google no personal information will be used unless you click on the corresponding icon. In case you have a Google+ account and are logged in while browsing stylebop.com, the information about your IP address will be used by Google. You can prevent this by logging out of your Google+ account while browsing our website. 

We are not able to influence which information is used and stored by Google. You will find further information on Google+ data processing under <http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html>

You will find the Google privacy policy under <http://www.google.com/intl/de/privacypolicy.html#information>.

7.3. Twitter

Twitter is a microblogging service owned by Twitter, Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA. When you browse our website and use Twitter icon your browser will automatically connect with Twitter servers and load the plug-in. In this case Twitter will automatically receive the information that the plug-in was activated on stylebop.com. Twitter can use and store user information after you click on the corresponding icon even if you are not logged in on Twitter. If you are logged in on Twitter while browsing our website Twitter can allocate your activity to your Twitter account.

If you click on the Twitter icon and twitter the information from the pop-up window, the information is transferred to Twitter. This information will then be posted in your Twitter profile.

You will find further information on data processing and your corresponding rights in the Twitter privacy policy under <http://twitter.com/privacy> abrufbar ist.

7.4. Pinterest

Pinterest is a social network owned by Pinterest, Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA, 94301, USA. When you browse our website and use Pin-it plug-in your browser will automatically connect with Pinterest servers and load the plug-in. In this case Pinterest may receive the information that you browsed our website from your IP address. When you click on Pin-it icon while you are logged in by Pinterest, you can share the information in your Pinterest profile. You can find the Pinterest privacy policy under [http://de.about.pinterest.com/privacy/](http://de.about.pinterest.com/privacy).

You can find information on how to prevent data use by Pinterest under https://help.pinterest.com/de/articles/personalization-and-data-other-websites.

* * *

### 8\. Sharing your personal data with third parties

Your personal data will not be shared with third parties unless we must do this in accordance with the existing laws (for example in case of a court order) or we have the right to do this (for example sharing the information with technical providers) or in case you explicitly give us the permission to share your personal information with third parties.

* * *

### 9\. Links to other websites

Our online services contain hyperlinks to websites that are owned and operated by other organisations. They control how your personal information is used when you give it to these other organisations or they collect it with cookies. We cannot influence this. You can find all the necessary information in the privacy policy of the corresponding company. We are not liable for any data use and procession carried out by third parties. If you use these other websites, you do so at your own risk.

* * *

### 10\. Security

STYLEBOP takes certain technical and organizational measures in order to protect stylebop.com against misuse and to protect your personal information against loss, manipulation and unauthorised use. The data transfer between our website and your browser is encrypted. We protect the transfer of your data with a secure SSL (Secure Socket Layer) connection. This technology prevents the unauthorised use of the transferred data by third parties. Most up-to-date browsers support this encryption technology.

Please note that email communication with STYLEBOP is not encrypted, which means that information contained in emails may be read by unauthorised third parties.

* * *

### 11\. Right for information and cancellation 

According to § 34 Federal Data Protection Act you have the right to receive the information about stored personal data at any time. If you gave us the permission for the use of your personal data, you can cancel it any time. You will find the contact information in our [Imprint](https://www.stylebop.com/en-de/women/imprint). 

* * *

November 2016
